Guide to the Robert Grenier Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series X. Magazines RG In and/or Associated With 1959 - 1998, Alphabetized and inventoried (by volume, number, date & RG's occurrence therein) - 2½ boxes.
  - F. BEZOAR, ed. Fred Buck & Paul Kahn, (17 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 17. Vol. 20, No. 4/Vol. 21, No. 1 (February 1981), Larry Eigner, Robert Grenier
      - "Draft of opening sequence / another go at / A DAY AT THE BEACH", poems by RG
  - G. BIG DEAL, No. 1 (Spring 1973), ed. Barbara Baracks (Box 26)
    - "roar of the tumblers" & "PUSH PUSH / northern fair gales", poems by RG (from SENTENCES period)
  - H. BLITZ-KLANG!, unnumbered (1986), ed. Paul Batlan & Benjamin Friediander (Box 26)
    - "PRAYER FOR BOOM", poem by RG (in Phantom Anthems)
  - I. BUDDHIST PEACE FELLOWSHIP NEWSLETTER, unnumbered (Winter 1991), ed. Susan Moon (Box 26)
    - "THIS YEAR", poem by RG
  - J. BULLETIN A.R.C. LITTÉRATURE, No. 162, on occasion of pub. of 21 + 1 POÈTES AMÉRICAINS D'AUJOURD'HUI, ed. Emmanuel Hocquard
    - "Toile à rayures", RG poem trans. by Ph. Jaworski
  - K. CHUMOLUNGMA GLOBE, No. 1 (Halloween 1987), ed. Andrew Schelling & Benjamin Friedlander (Box 26)
    - notebook page re "'time' in the work" by RG
  - L. CLOUD MARAUDER, No. 4 (1968), ed. David Bullen, Don Cushman, Dennis Koran & Anthony Shonwald (Box 26)
    - "Boylston Hall", poem by RG
  - M. CREDENCES 7, Vol. 3, No. 1 (February 1979), ed. Robert Bertholf, issue in celebration of Kenneth Irby (Box 26)
  - N. DARK AGES CLASP THE DAISY ROOT, ed. Andrew Schelling & Benjamin Friedlander, (4 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. No. 1 (November 1989)
    - 2. No. 2 (February 1990)
    - 3. No. 3 (June 1990)
    - 4. No. 5 (March 1991)
      - "A CONVERSATION WITH ALASTAIR JOHNSTON / ROBERT GRENIER (February 12, 1987)", transcribed by RG & AJ
      - 5. No. 7 (April 1992)
  - 0. DELUGE, No. 1 (1990), ed. Daniel McNaughton (Box 26)
    - "SUN DOWN", "IMAGE", BLUE EYES" & "was a rose", poems by RG
  - P. DISTURBED GUILLOTINE, No. 2 (Winter/Spring 1995-96), ed. Frederic Hausmann (Box 26)
    - "FOR EMILY LORD & ROBERT T .S. LOWELL", poem by RG
  - Q. FOOT, No. 8 (1980), ed. Richard Duerden & Leslie Scalapino (Box 26)
    - "THIS OBSCURE", "KNOCK WOULD EXPLAIN NOTHING" & "sun on my west", poems by RG
  - R. GAS, unnumbered (Winter 1990), ed. Kevin Opstedal & Charlie Ross (Box 26)
    - "MOO", poem by RG
  - S. GEMS, Vol. 3 (Minneapolis English Teachers' Club, May 1959), ed. Stuart Telecky (in IV.E.5 above) (Box 26)
    - "COMMUNION", poem by RG (lst pub. poem)
  - T. GOOD SHIT, unnumbered (November 1970), ed. C.C. Carlsen (work by Tufts U. students of RG) (Box 26)
    - "STORM WINDOWS", "FALL", "THE TREES" & "LOW ON CASH", poems by RG (from Series)
  - U. GORILLA POETRY JOURNAL, Vol. 1, No. 1 (May 1970), ed. Hersha Steinbock & Penelope Lowenthal (U.C./Berkeley student magazine) (Box 26)
    - "Memory", poem by RG
  - V. GUM, ed. Dave Morice, (6 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. No. 2 (September 1970)
    - 2. No. 3 (October 1970)24 poems by RG (many later collected in Series)
    - 3. No. 5 (June 1971)
      - 9 poems by RG (3 collected in Series, 1 in SENTENCES)
    - 4. No. 6 (September 1971)
      - "BELLS AT SEA" (in SENTENCES), "sunlight" & "eyes", poems by RG
    - 5. No. 8 (May 1972)
      - "what's/after tourists" & "Maury/+/Betty Fletcher" (in SENTENCES), poems by RG
    - 6. No. 9 (January 1973)
      - "he was/so shaped" & "look at his little pink tongue", poems by RG
  - W. HILLS, ed. Michael Waltuch (#1 only) & Bob Perelman, (5 issues) (Box 26)
    - 1. No. 1 (March 1973)
    - 2. No. 2, (ca. 1973)
      - 24 poems by RG (many in SENTENCES)
    - 3. No. 3 (April 1976)
      - "GUACAMOLE", poem by RG
    - 4. No. 4 (May 1977)
    - 5. No. 9 (Spring 1983)
  - X. I AM A CHILD, No. 1 (April 1994), ed. William Howe & Benjamin Friedlander (Box 26)
    - "FIRE AWAY", "Solution", "BOMB", "HORRIBLE", "Conservation Of/ Resources", "Knowledge" & "For Genie", poems by RG
  - Y. IN PRINT, Vol. 4, No. 1 (Fall 1986), ed. Carl Carlsen (Box 26)
    - "Sixteen Rubber Two's", poem by RG (in Phantom Anthems)
  - Z. INTRO, No. 1 (September 1968), ed. R.V. Cassill (Box 26)
    - "The Poem With Her Name In It (by request)", poem by RG
  - AA. IRONWOOD, No. 20 (1982), ed. Michael Cuddihy, in "REALISM: AN ANTHOLOGY OF LANGUAGE POETS", ed. Ron Silliman (Box 26)
    - "Further Beach Poem Drafts", 9 poems by RG
  - AB. JIMMY & LUCY'S HOUSE OF "K", ed. Andrew Schelling & Benjamin Friedlander, (3 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. No. 2 (August 1984)
      - "HAS FADED IN PART BUT MAGNIFICENT ALSO LATE", poem by RG (in Phantom Anthems & Postmodern American Poetry)
      - RG note on "TENNYSON (A PERFORMANCE BY STEPHEN RODEFER)"
      - Larry Eigner note on RG's work, "NOT TOO FAST, EITHER / (SO DOES TIME MUCH MATTER ?)"
    - 2. No. 5 (November 1985)
      - "VOCALIC COTTONWOODS", poem by RG (insert page)
      - "MIKE AND MACK AT THE SHORE", review of RG's At The Beach by Tom Beckett
    - 3. No. 8 (January 1988)
  - AC. L MAGAZINE, ed. Curtis Faville, (5 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. Vol. 1, No. 1 (1972)
      - 6 poems by RG (1 in SENTENCES)
    - 2. Vol. 1, Nos. 2-3 (Spring 1973)
      - "local road", poem by RG
    - 3. Vol. 2, Nos. 1-2 (Spring 1974)
      - 10 poems by RG (many in SENTENCES)
  - AD. L=A=N=G=U=A=G=E, ed. Bruce Andrews & Charles Bernstein, (12 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. Vol. 1, No. 1 (February 1978)
    - 2. Vol. 1, No. 2 (April 1978>)
    - 3. Vol. 1, No. 3 (June 1978)
    - 4. Vol. 1, No. 4 (August 1978)
      - "THINK SUN AND SEE SHADOW", verse collage from work of Louis Zukofsky by RG
    - 5. Vol. 1, No. 5 (October 1978)
      - "HEDGE-CRICKETS SING", note on Keats' sound by RG
      - "GRENIER'S SENTENCES" by Barrett Watten
    - 6. Vol. 1, No. 6 (December 1978)
      - "TENDER BUTTONS", note on Gertrude Stein by RG
    - 7. Vol. 2, No. 7 (March 1979)
    - 8. Vol. 2, No. 8 (June 1979)
      - "WRITING IS AN AID TO MEMORY", note on Lyn Hejinian by RG
    - 9. Vol. 3, No. 11 (January 1980)
      - Michael Gottlieb note on RG's CAMBRIDGE M'ASS
    - 10. Vol. 3, No. 12 June 1980)
    - 11. Supplement No. 1 (June 1980)
    - 12. Supplement No. 2 (June 1980)
  - AE. LINES, ed. Aram Saroyan, (three issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. No. 1 (September 1964)
      - "Old Blue Sneakers", "Tune For Beanie", "Dusk Road Game" & "A Sort Of Plea", poems by RG (in Dusk Road Games)
    - 2. No. 2 (December 1964)
      - "The Light", poem by RG (in Dusk Road Games)
    - 3. No. 3 (February 1965)
  - AF. MYSTICRIVERREADER, No. 1 (April 1971), ed. Jed Myers (poems by Tufts. U. students of RG) (Box 26)
    - "SATURDAY", "gost" (in Series), "the arm form" & "EMILY", poems by RG
  - AG. NOTES, No. 1 (May 1980), ed. Emmanuel Hocquard & Claude Royet-Journoud, in Anthology of One-Line Poems (Box 26)
    - "FINCHES" by RG (in A Day At The Beach)
    - AH. O No. 4 (1993), ed. Leslie Scalapino, Subliminal Time issue (Box 26)
      - "my heart is beating / I am a beast", 4 blue/green versions of RG holograph Drawing poems traced by LS for mag's covers
      - 8 blue/green poems from RG r h y m m s project
  - Al. PENINSULA, No. 3 (1989), ed. Joe Safdie (Box 26)
    - 10 RG holograph Drawing poems from Transpiration/Transpiring
  - AJ. POETRY (Chicago), Vol. 112, No. 2 (May 1968), ed. Henry Rago (Box 26)
    - "WARM" (in Series), "ST. EMILY OF THE BODY" & "BIRD SONG", poems by RG
  - AK. QUARK, No. 1 (November 1967), ed. Diane Neumaier, Everett Frost & Barry Casselman (Box 26)
    - "THE BICYCLISTS" & "SITTING ALONE OUTSIDE IN A MAY MORNING", poems by RG
  - AL. ROOF, ed. James Sherry, (6 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. Vol. 1, No. 2 (Spring 1977)
    - 2. Vol. 1, No. 3 (Summer 1977)
    - 3. Vol. 1, No. 4 (Fall 1977)
    - 4. Vol. 2, No. 1 (Winter1978)
    - 5. Vol. 2, No. 4 (Winter 1978)
      - Larry Eigner poems, ed. RG
    - 6. Vol. 3, No. 1 (Spring 1979)
  - AM. SMELT MONEY, No. 2 (1994), ed. Jim McCrary (Box 26)
    - 2 RG holograph Drawing poems from Transpiration/Transpiring
  - AN. SMITHEREENS SEASONAL SAMPLER, Vol. 1, No. 2 (1982), ed. Charlie Ross (Box 26)
    - "MY WEENY", poem by RG
  - AO. SPLASH, Vol. 1, No. 1 (July 1984), ed. Wystan Curnow & Tony Green (Box 26)
    - 30 RG poems from A Day At The Beach
  - AP. STATIONS, No. 5 (Winter 1978), A Symposium on Clark Coolidge, ed. Ron Silliman (Box 26)
    - "Notes on Coolidge, Objectives, Zukofsky, Romanticism And &", essay by RG
  - AQ. SULFUR, ed. Clayton Eshleman, (2 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. SULFUR 20, Vol. 7, No. 2 (Fall 1987)
      - "TONGUES OF ANGEL MAKE / FOR UNION WITH THE MAKE", note on Alice Notley's PARTS OF A WEDDING by RG
    - 2. SULFUR 23, Vol. 8, No. 2 (Fall 1988)
      - "I HAD NO IDEA / PICK UP THE HOUSE!", note on Anselm Hollo's PICK UP THE HOUSE! by RG
  - AR. SUM, ed. Fred Wah, (3 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. No. 1 (December 1963)
      - "Through (Where) Walls (Were)" (in Dusk Road Games) & "3 A.M. In The Back Room", poems by RG
    - 2. No. 2 (February 1964)
      - "The Ritual Bath", poem by RG (in Dusk Road Games)
    - 3. No. 3 (May 1964)
  - AS. TALISMAN, No. 1 (Fall 1988), ed. Edward Foster (Box 26)
    - "YOUR GARDEN", "BEAUTY" & "LE JARDIN ARTISTIC", poems by RG (from What I Believe)
  - AT. TAMARIND, ed. Marcia Lawther (+ friends in NYC collective), unnumbered (12 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. October 1980
    - 2. February 1981
    - 3. May 1981
    - 4. June 1981
    - 5. July 1981
    - 6. September 1981
    - 7. December 1981
    - 8. January 1982
    - 9. March 1982
      - "Beach Poem" by Marcia Lawther (for RG)
      - "Further Beach Poem Drafts", poems by RG
    - 10. June 1982
    - 11. August 1982
      - Larry Eigner letter to Marcia Lawther re RG etc.
      - Larry Eigner poems for RG
    - 12. January 1983
      - w/ Marcia Lawther letter to RG
  - AU. :that:, ed. Stephen Ellis & Stephen Dignazio, (23 issues total) (Box 26)
    - 1. No. 3 (June 1992), Ed Foster, Margueritte
    - 2. No. 4 (July 1992), Michael Breiner, Mike Boughn
    - 3. No. 5 (September 1992), Karen DBiscoll, Stephen Ratcliffe
    - 4. No. 6 (October 1992), Theodore Enslin, Thomas Taylor
    - 5. No. 7 (November 1992), Richard Grazide, Joel Lewis
    - 6. No. 8 (December 1992), Susan Smith Nash, Jim McCrary
    - 7. No. 9 (January 1993), Richard Blevins, Cathleen Shattuck
    - 8. No. 10 (March 1993), David Bromige, A.L. Nielsen
    - 9. No. 11 (April 1993), Spencer Selby, Duncan McNaughton
    - 10. No. 12 (May 199), Peter Ganick, Michael Leddy
    - 11. No. 13 (July 1993), Philip Sittnick, Michael Basinski
    - 12. No. 14 (August 1993), Robert Creeley, Benjamin Friedlander
    - 13. No. 15 (October 1993), Mark DuCharme
    - 14. No. 16 (November 1993), Joe Napora, Kenneth Warren
    - 15. No. 17 (December 1993), Joseph Torra, Robert Sheppard
    - 16. No. 18 (February 1994), Daniel Zimmerman
    - 17. No. 19 (February 1994), Kenneth Irby, Patrick Doud
    - 18. No. 20 April 1994), Nathaniel Tarn
    - 19. No. 21 (June 1994), Bruce Andrews, Ray DiPalma
    - 20. No. 22 (June 1994), Clayton Eshleman, Halliday Dresser
    - 21. No. 23 (July 1994), Stephen Jonas
    - 22. No. 24 (August 1994), Robert Grenier (in VIII, RG Book Manuscripts, above)
      - 14 pages of RG holograph drawing poems from r h y m m s project (black/white versions of color images)
    - 23. Second Series, No. 1 (1996), Robert Grenier (in V.ca.l7 above)
      - "GRENIER TALK: FROST PLACE, FRANCONIA NH, 08.06.93" & two RG color holograph drawing poems on front/back covers
  - AV. THE, No. 6 (1970), ed. Jack Collom (in III.A.11, Larry Eigner Materials, above) (Box 26)
  - AW. THE AMERICAN BOOK REVIEW, Vol. 2, No. 1 (Summer 1979), ed. Charles Russell & Suzanne Zarrian (Box 26)
    - SENTENCES by RG, reviewed by Ron Silliman
  - AX. THE ANTIOCH REVIEW, Vol. 30, Nos. 3-4 (Fall/Winter 1970-71), ed. Lawrence Grauman, Jr., Gordon Cairnie Birthday Section (Box 27)
    - "STRIPED CANVAS", poem by RG (in Series)
    - Elsa Dorfman photo of RG
  - AY. THE BOSTON REVIEW, Vol. 1, No. 1 (Fall 1966), ed. Stephen Saltonstall & Timothy Mayo (Box 27)
    - "FOR DONALD JUSTICE", "GOING TO BED", "& BASEBALL CAPS & MUD GUARDS", "DIFFICULT APARTMENT HUNTING WITH A FRIEND", "FIRST SETTLEMENT AND AFTER", "UNSENT LETTER TO HIS WIFE", poems by RG (in Dusk Road Games)
    - "Or: Bright Mind Over Matter Though He Says He Doesn't", RG note on work of Sidney Goldfarb
  - AZ. THE DIFFICULTIES, Vol. 3, No. 1 (1987), ed. Tom Beckett, David Bromige Issue (Box 27)
    - "TO SEE OURSELVES AS OTHERS SEE US", RG note on David Bromige
  - BA. THE FRANCONIA REVIEW, ed. Franconia College students & faculty advisors David Ackley & RG, (7 issues total) (Box 27)
    - 1. Vol. 1, No. 1 (Winter 1971)
    - 2. Vol. 2 ('1'?), No. 1 ('2'?) (1971)
      - "Sticky Fingers", poem by RG (in Series)
    - 3. Vol. 1, No. 2 (Spring 1972)
      - "clouded/over/without", "slew" (in SENTENCES) & "course/ of the/bright sunshine", poems by RG
    - 4. Vol. 1, No. 3 (Autumn 1972)
      - "can stay apart", "transference isolates", "shadow like Iowa", "having eaten something up", "barking because it's landlord" (in SENTENCES), "s p a c e a s e" & "corn clouds inveterate", poems by RG
    - 5. Vol. 3, No. 1 (1973)
      - "PUSH PUSH/northern fair gales", "sing songs to crop duster" & "they are naturally hostile to getting picked off", poems by RG (in SENTENCES)
    - 6. Vol. 4, No. 2 (1974)
    - 7. Vol. 5, No. 2 (1975)
      - 20 "separate poems" from SENTENCES period by RG
  - BB. THE HARVARD ADVOCATE, (6 issues total) (Box 27)
    - 1. Vol. 97, No. 2 (January 1963), ed. Michael Cain & Sidney Goldfarb
      - "A Race" & "The Lecture", poems by RG
    - 2. Vol. 97, No. 3 (Spring 1963), ed. M. Cain & S. Goldfarb
      - "The Formal Bells", "in their small rooms", "The Depth of Fall", "Goodbye", "A Sort Of Renewal" (in Dusk Road Games), "The Words", "Pigeons" & "Very Clearly One Morning", poems by RG
    - 3. Vol. 98, No. 1 (Fall 1963), ed. M. Cain & S. Goldfarb
      - "In The Barn", "Through (Where) Walls (Were)" & "Husband", poems by RG (in Dusk Road Games)
      - "Along The Shore Of An Old Lake" & "Nightfall", RG translations from German of Georg Trakl
      - RG review of The Island by Robert Creeley
    - 4. Vol. 98, No. 2 (Summer 1964), ed. William Ferguson
      - "Listening" & "Slum Spring", poems by RG
      - "New Wine", RG trans. from German of Georg Trakl
    - 5. Vol. 99, No. 1 (November 1964), ed. William Ferguson
      - "You", "Moon", "Leaf" (in Dusk Road Games), "Heritage" & "The Puzzle", poems by RG
    - 6. Vol. 101, No. 3 (December 1967), ed. Robert Shaw
      - "A Post-Freudian Dickens" by Richard Tillinghast, review of RG's Dusk Road Games (Pym-Randall Press, 1967) (in III.B.23 above)
  - BC. THE LITTLE MAGAZINE, Vol. 20 (1994), ed. David Coogan (in V.C.16 above) (Box 27)
    - "INTERVIEW WITH ROBERT GRENIER", July 9, 1992 by Rebecca Bush
    - "BJELDANES SERIES", RG holograph Drawing poems (black/white versions of color images)
  - BD. THE PARIS REVIEW, Vol. 24, No. 85 (Fall 1982), ed. Donald Hall, in "Language Sampler", ed. Charles Bernstein (Box 27)
    - "Six Poems" by RG (from A Day At The Beach period)
  - BE. THE WORLD, (2 issues total) (Box 27)
    - 1. No. 37 (December 1982), ed. Harris Schiff
      - 10 poems from A Day At The Beach by RG
    - 2. No. 38 (1983), ed. Unspecified
      - "FUNDAMENTAL" & "HELP", poems by RG
  - BF. THIS, (12 issues total: whole set) (Box 27)
    - 1. No. 1 (Winter 1971), ed. Barrett Watten & Robert Grenier
      - "nights now", "PLOWS/by", "THROUGH THE SPACE BETWEEN", "SHARPS/in the cold", "SNAPS/get it to cook", "RED WREATHS", "LOOKING", "WINTRY", "NOW IT IS" & "THE CEILING IS GRADUALLY FILLING IN", poems by RG (in Series)
      - RG review of Robert Creeley's A Quick Graph: Collected Notes & Essays (Four Seasons, 1970)
      - RG note/manifesto "ON SPEECH"
      - RG review of Robert Creeley's Pieces (Scribner's, 1969)
      - RG collage/review of Gertrude Stein's Lectures in America (Beacon, 1957)
      - RG note on Edward Lear's The Complete Nonsense Book (Duffield & Co., 1912)
    - 2. No. 2 (Fall 1971), ed. B. Watten & R. Grenier
      - 34 poems by RG (from early SENTENCES period)
      - RG note on Aram Saroyan's work, "For Aram Saroyan, Who Tells The Truth"
      - RG note on William Carlos Williams' Spring & All (Frontier Press, 1970)
    - 3. No. 3 (Fall 1972), ed. B. Watten & R. Grenier
      - "sure arm today", "refrigerator so long", "walking down Washington Avenue", "combination rafter and", "choir tea", "Dream/y belly", "date o dot", "THE HORSE WRESTLES/THE HOSS WRESTLERS", "with his ka", "s o m e o l d g u y s w i t h s c y t h e s", "QUIET T/so shone", poems by RG (from SENTENCES period)
      - RG endnote, "FOUR FOR TO TWO / SEEING THROUGH THE ROUND"
    - 4. No. 4 (Spring 1973), ed. B. Watten & R. Grenier
    - 5. No. 5 (Winter 1974), ed. B. Watten & R. Grenier
      - 30 poems by RG (from SENTENCES period) (insert on cards)
    - 6. No. 6 (Spring 1975), ed. B. Watten
    - 7. No. 7 (Spring 1976), ed. B. Watten
      - "NORTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE", prose/verse 'story' by RG
    - 8. No. 8 (Spring 1977), ed. B. Watten
      - "53 separate poems from 'work in progress'" by RG (some in SENTENCES, some in CAMBRIDGE M'ASS)
    - 9. No. 9 (Winter 1978-79), ed. B. Watten
    - 10. No. 10 (Winter 1979-80), ed. B. Watten
    - 11. No. 11 (Spring 1981), ed. B. Watten
      - RG translation of excerpt from Bertolt Brecht's Das Badener Lehrstück Vom Einverständnis (The Baden-Baden Instructional Play Concerning Understanding)
    - 12. No. 12 (Fall 1982), ed. Barrett Watten
      - 15 poems by RG (in A Day At The Beach)
  - BG. TOTTEL'S, ed. Ron Silliman, (8 issues total) (Box 27)
    - 1. No. 1, undated (ca. 1971)
      - "within the family/there are sweet exchanges", "STEAM/ inside", "PAINTINGS/lamb stew", "JOY/maple/apple" & "FALL", poems by RG (in Series)
    - 2. No. 2 (March 1971)
    - 3. No. 4 (July 1971)
    - 4. No. 5 (September 1971)
      - 20 poems by RG (from early SENTENCES period)
    - 5. No. 6 (October 1971)
    - 6. No. 8 (1972)
    - 7. No. 10 (Fall 1972)
      - 6 poems by RG (from early SENTENCES period)
    - 8. No. 17 (1978)
  - BH. TYUONYI, Nos. 6-7 (1990), ed. Phillip Foss & Charles Bernstein (Box 27)
    - "POET FELT", verse commentary by RG
  - BI. VANISHING CAB, No. 6 (1984), ed. Jerry Estrin (Box 27)
    - "PREWAR LATE OCTOBER SEA BREEZE", poem by RG (in Phantom Anthems)
  - BJ. WCH WAY, No. 5 (1984), ed. Don Byrd & Jed Rasula (Box 27)
    - 12 poems by RG (in Phantom Anthems)
  - BK. WITZ, ed. Christopher Reiner, (4 issues total) (Box 27)
    - 1. Vol. 2, No. 2 (Spring 1994) (in V.C.7 above)
      - "COLLOQUY / DAVID BROMIGE/ROBERT GRENIER", excerpt from conversation between DB & RG, July 3, 1986
    - 2. Vol. 3, No. 2 (Spring 1995)
      - RG review of Don Byrd's The Poetics of the Common Knowledge (SUNY Press, 1993)
    - 3. Unnumbered (Spring 1996)
      - "Grenier's 'Scrawl'", Stephen Ratcliffe essay on RG color holograph drawing poems from r h y m m s project
    - 4. Vol. 5, No. 1 (Spring 1997)
- Series XI. Color Slides Made by Photographer Ken Botto and RG (of RG Color Holograph Drawing Poems from r h y m m s Project 1989 - 1998), As of April 15, 1999 being 1,285 'spare' slides in 27 slide boxes, labeled by year and counted - ½ box.
  COMMENT: Beginning in the summer of 1992, RG began engaging photographer Ken Botto to help document/extract images from RG's ongoing color holograph drawing poem project, r h y m m s, initially to preserve 'better' images (in case notebooks themselves were lost/destroyed etc.) & because the other available means of 'publication', color xeroxing, was (& continues to be) so expensive. Slides are taken outdoors in Bolinas in horizontal late afternoon sunshine to minimize shadows & maximize color (RG holding notebook open while KB shoots away, it being often hot & difficult/exacting labor). It became soon evident that the slides thus produced were not only preserving images, but were collaborative works in themselves--further/original ('literary') occasions in which words reside, in very different ways from those possible in the materials of notebook pages or color xerography. In 1992 RG began showing/interpreting slides as a form of 'poetry reading'/public performance of the text--so that people could literally see what letters/words have to say. These slides also have begun to make possible 'publication' of work from RG's ongoing r h y m m s project in digital form on the Web (via 'translations' from slides by Karl Young & others, see XII.R.3. below). Another (expensive!) possibility is to make large prints from selected slides (as KB does w/ his own photographs) for gallery exhibit.
  At 1999 Apr 15, there are some several thousand r h y m m s slides in RG's possession. The 1,285 slides inventoried herein are what RG can 'spare' (2 slides are taken of each original drawing poem) now. Eventually the RG Archive should include one slide of each original.
  - A. 1992 Botto Spares, (2 boxes/114 slides total) (Box 028)
    - 1. Box 1, (43 slides)
      - a slide of RG holding green r h y m m s box, (designed to hold ca. 90 8½" by 11" color xerox images)
      - 2 slides of RG holding notebook open for photographing
      - 40 full-page notebook slides
    - 2. Box 2, (71 slides)
      - 71 full-page notebook slides
  - B. 1993 Botto Spares, (1 box/9 slides total) (Box 028)
    - 9 full-page notebook slides
  - C. 1994 Botto Spares, (3 boxes/95 slides total) (Box 028)
    - 1. Box 1, (44 slides) 44 full-page notebook slides
    - 2. Box 2, (21 slides) 21 full-page notebook slides
    - 3. Box 3, (30 slides) 30 half-page notebook slides
  - D. 1995 Botto Spares, (3 boxes/109 slides total) (Box 028)
    - 1. Box 1, (38 slides) 38 full-page notebook slides
    - 2. Box 2, (43 slides) 43 half-page notebook slides
    - 3. Box 3, (28 slides) 28 half-page notebook slides
  - E. 1996 Botto Spares, (2 boxes/98 slides total) (Box 028)
    - 1. Box 1, (55 slides) 55 half-page notebook slides
    - 2. Box 2, (43 slides) 43 half-page notebook slides (most of RG work called For Larry Eigner, missing poems #6 ("moon/O/letters/ plage") & #45 ("heart/in/dark")) (see XII.R.2. below)
  - F. 1997 Botto Spares, (3 boxes/108 slides total) (Box 028)
    - 1. Box 1, (48 slides) 48 full-page slides of whole tiny notebook (all of RG works called Greeting & Pond I) (see XII.R.3. below)
    - 2. Box 2, (34 slides) 34 full-page notebook slides (material gathered toward unpublished RG work Pond II)
    - 3. Box 3, (26 slides) 26 slides of RG drawing poems on large loose pages (more material toward unpublished work Pond II)
  - G. 1998 Botto Spares, (13 boxes/752 slides total) (all full-page notebook slides) (Box 028)
    These slides are arranged in chronological order & document the beginnings of RG's developing relation w/ Susan Friedland (& represent a 'first draft' of RG work devoted to same)
    - 1. Box 1, (53 slides)
    - 2. Box 2, (53 slides)
    - 3. Box 3, (51 slides)
    - 4. Box 4, (58 slides)
    - 5. Box 5, (61 slides)
    - 6. Box 6, (62 slides)
    - 7. Box 7, (63 slides)
    - 8. Box 8, (63 slides)
    - 9. Box 9, (62 slides)
    - 10. Box 10, (52 slides)
    - 11. Box 11, (61 slides)
    - 12. Box 12, (63 slides)
    - 13. Box 13, (50 slides)
- Series XII. RG Published Works 1967 - 1998, Signed copies of RG publications (e.g. SENTENCES, Burns' Night Heard, Oakland, etc.) needed to complete RG Archive collection - 1 box.
  - A. Two New Poems, a chapbook pub. by James Randall's Pym-Randall Press in Cambridge, MA in 1967, Containing RG's "Warm" (later collected in Series) & "Sitting Alone Outside In A May Morning" (otherwise unpublished) & announcing forthcoming publication of Dusk Road Games (4 pp. total) (Box 029)